Guide to the John G. Younger Papers, 1976-2001
Duke University. University Archives
John G. Younger papers 1976-2001
Duke University. University Archives
Younger, John G.
1.5 linear feet Extent: 1000 Items
John G. Younger graduated from Stanford University in 1967 with a B. A. in History with Honors. At the University of Cincinnati, he earned an M. A. in Classics in 1969 and a Ph.D. in Classics in 1973. From 1973-1974, Dr. Younger taught at the Campion School in Athens Greece. From 1974-2002, he taught at Duke University, first as Assistant Professor of Classical Studies, then as Associate Professor and then Professor of Classical Archaeology. In 2002, Dr. Younger left Duke to teach at the University of Kansas as Professor in Classics and Humanities and Western Civilization. The collection contains records and papers concerning the FOCUS program, archaeology courses, gay activism and campus diversity issues. The materials include minutes and reports of the president's and other committees, correspondence, email, printed matter, financial records, photographs and drawings, archaeological reports and student course and term papers. The material ranges in date from 1976-2001.
UA.29.02.0090
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use. After twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist.
In accordance with the Family Education Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 as amended, Duke University permits students to inspect their education records and limits the disclosure of personally identifiable information from education records.
Portions of these materials are restricted by donor request.
In off-site storage; 48 hours advance notice is required for use.
Provenance
The John G. Younger Papers were received by the University Archives as a gift in 2001.
Biographical Note
John G. Younger graduated from Stanford University in 1967 with a B. A. in History with Honors. At the University of Cincinnati, he earned an M. A. in Classics in 1969 and a Ph.D. in Classics in 1973. From 1973-1974, Dr. Younger taught at the Campion School in Athens Greece. From 1974-2002, he taught at Duke University, first as Assistant Professor of Classical Studies, then as Associate Professor and then Professor of Classical Archaeology. In 2002, Dr. Younger left Duke to teach at the University of Kansas as Professor in Classics and Humanities and Western Civilization.
During his career, Dr. Younger has participated in excavations in Greece, Italy and Israel and is a member of both the American School of Classical Studies at Athens, Greece and the British School of Archaeology at Athens. His areas of specialization are the art and archaeology of pre-classical and classical Greece, Aegean seals, classical sculpture, gender and sexuality in the ancient world, Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual and Trans-gendered/Queer issues in academe, and internet technology and humanities computing.
Collection Overview
The collection contains records and papers concerning the FOCUS program, archaeology courses, gay activism and campus diversity issues. The materials include minutes and reports of the president's and other committees, correspondence, email, printed matter, financial records, photographs and drawings, archaeological reports and student course and term papers. Major subjects include the University's diversity awareness program, benefits for same-sex spousal equivalents, and gay life on campus, the administration of the FOCUS program, and the history and archaeology of East and West campuses and Duke Forest. Some student papers are graded and the files include other student-identifiable records. Also includes scripts of plays written by Duke alum Kevin Patterson and other writers. Patterson was a member of Duke Players and died of AIDS in New York. One of his plays, Allen Turing: The Most Secret War, was produced on Broadway. The collection includes an early draft of this piece. The material ranges in date from 1976-2001.
Subject Headings
Archaeology -- Study and teaching; Duke Forest (N.C.); Duke University -- Buildings -- History -- 20th century; Homosexuality and education -- North Carolina; Plays -- Collection
Related Material
News Service Biographical Files, 1960-2004
Biographical Reference Collection, 1972-2004
Duke University Archives
Contents of Collection
- John G. Younger Papers
  - Duke Allies: brochure, flier and personal recollections, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Campus Reports, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Diversity-Identity, FOCUS, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Diversity, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Diversity, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Diversity, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - FOCUS, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - FOCUS, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - FOCUS, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - FOCUS, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Same-sex spousal equivalent, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Same-sex spousal equivalent sheets (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Domestic Partners, 1990-1994 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Lesbian and Gay Studies Newsletter, 1991, 1993, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Duke LGBNet (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Dale Martin Committee, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Outlines newsletter of the Duke Gay, Lesbian, and Bisexual Association, 1995 May (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Duke Forest, archaeology reports, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Negatives and Photographs of East Campus Dig, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Student reports/projects from archaeology class and East Campus Dig, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Architecture, student papers (some with photographs), 1976-1980 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - The Stone Chronicles of Duke University: An Archaeological and Photographic Survey of West Campus (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Crisis at Trinity, play by John Merritt, revised 1992 November (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Creative Comforts, play by Kevin Patterson, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Safe Harbor, play by Kevin Patterson, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Allen Turing: The Most Secret War, early draft, by Kevin Patterson, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Unidentified Play (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Sancutary (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - A Most Secret War program and flier for Fascination Cha-Cha, Kevin Patterson plays (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Five O'Clock Ladies, play by James Drew, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Ulysses in Traction, by Albert Innaurato (Box 1, Folder 31)